《越狱》第四季 第十六集
Prison.Break.S04E16
《越狱》  前情回顾
previously on prison break.
手术的代价是把"锡拉"安全找回来
the price of the operation is the safe return of scylla.
看看买家有没有留消息
see if the buyer left him a message.
是迈阿密的区号
yeah, it's a miami area code.
东西
the item.
我确信你们明白
i'm sure you understand no one can know
不能让人知道"锡拉"的去向
where scylla's going.
你知道是谁拿走了吗
do you know who took it?
不  但赛尔夫和格雷琴知道
no, but self and gretchen do.
那你就有队友了
then you've got your team.
我不会和他们一起工作
i'm not working for them.
你简历中的空白
there are holes in your resume
格雷琴或赛尔夫  甚至巴格维尔都能填补
that gretchen or self or even bagwell can fill.
出什么事了
what happened?
他逃走了
he got away.
这是什么
what's this?
我的辞呈
my resignation.
无论你有什么计划把我们从这弄出去
whatever plan you're working on to get us out of here,
我们最好有所行动
we better make a move on it.
迈克尔  你不能离开这里
you're not getting out of here, michael.
我做了个交易
i made a deal.
用"锡拉"换回你的命
your life in exchange for scylla.
就凭你对"公司"的了解
you think you can do that
你以为你能做到吗
knowing what you know about the company?
你想知道我对"公司"的了解吗
you want to know what i know about the company?
妈妈生前一直为他们卖命
mom worked for them before she died.
我会竭尽所能结束这一切
now, i'm gonna do everything and anything i can to end this.
喂
hello?
莎拉  是我
sara, it's me.
你在哪
where are you?
迈阿密  偷走"锡拉"的人在这
miami. the guy who took scylla's here.
你真的要帮"公司"找回"锡拉"吗
so you're-you're actually trying to get it back for the company?
只有这样  我们才能
i'm gonna give it back to the company so we can
摆脱这一切
walk away from this.
迈克尔怎么样了
how's michael?
我不知道
i don't know.
我不知道  "公司"派来两个人
i don't know. two guys from the company came,
把我带到一个宾馆
and they brought me to a hotel,
还送给我  花
and-and i was given... flowers
和一个果篮
and a fruit basket,
迈克尔的事连一个字都没提
and absolutely no information about michael.
费尔南多和你在一起吗
is fernando with you?
他走了
sucre split.
我们给马宏留了消息
we, uh, we left some messages
告诉他
with mahone, telling him
我们在什么地方
where we are, but that
但是两个电话都没通
was two cell phones back.
我们是指谁  你和谁在一起
sorry, who's "we"? who are you with?
我不信任的人
people i don't trust.
好吧
okay.
听我说
listen, um...
林肯  我知道你为什么要这么做
lincoln, i know why you did it, and-and...
我很感激你  因为迈克尔当时命悬一线
i'm grateful to you, because he was gonna die.
但是  你真的认为
but do you really think that
他们拿到"锡拉"后  会放过我们吗
they're just gonna let us live when we give them scylla?
莎拉  我尽力而为吧
you know what, sara, i'm doing my best.
如果有迈克尔的消息
just-just call me
请给我打电话
if you hear anything about michael, please.
林肯  "公司"的信息部
linc, the company's data tech
终于找到那个人的电话了
finally got a hit on our guy's cell phone.
追查到一个地址
it's a number, and it goes to this address--
格拉夫顿  是个酒吧
the grafton; it's a club.
他打了几个电话
how many calls?
三个  都是打出去的
three. all outgoing.
我们如何得知
how do we know this guy's
他还在迈阿密
still in miami,
而且没有把"锡拉"卖出去
that he hasn't sold it already, huh?
我不是抱怨什么
not that i'm complaining.
我在这个州可有过不少"历史"
i've had some filthy, filthy times in this state.
千万别搞砸了
don't screw this up, all right?
这可是我们唯一的线索
because that's our only lead on this guy.
你应该感谢我当时没杀你
be thankful i haven't killed you.
是吗  你以为你是埃利奥特・奈斯吗[联邦神探]
oh, yeah? wh-what are you, eliot ness now? huh?
因为我骗了你们  你还在生气吗
what, are you upset because i screwed you over, linc?
别装得好像
'cause don't act like
你从来没对别人做过同样的事
you haven't done that to ten times as many people.
我们都一样  林肯
all right? we're just crooks that got caught, lincoln.
这个
this...
这小子  他去是没用的
this guy, this isn't gonna work.
我们还是关注"锡拉"在谁手里吧
why don't we all just focus on who's got scylla.
你觉得呢
what do you say?
斯科菲尔德
hey, scofield.
我在什么地方
where am i?
他醒了
he's awake.
我到底在哪
i said, where am i?
树林里的一座房子
it's a house, in the woods,
位于某处60英里外
60 miles from anywhere.
没有武器
swept clean of weapons, so you don't need
所以你不用白费心机了
to worry your head about that.
窗户和门上都没有栏杆
there are no bars on the windows or the doors,
但附近区域有三种美洲狮出没
but there are three types of mountain lion in the area,
所以你最好呆在这里
so you might want to stay close by.
我来说吧
i'll take it from here.
我是罗杰・诺顿医生  迈克尔
dr. roger knowlton, michael.
你感觉怎么样
how are you feeling?
你是神经科医生吗
you some kind of neurologist?
精神病医生
psychiatrist.
将军说  你有不少空闲时间
given that you've got some free time,
让我和你谈谈
the general asked if i'd sit with you.
雪茄是用来抽的
a cigar's a cigar.
说完了吧
are we done?
你的行动都是建立在
you've been operating under some...
对"公司"的错误看法上的
misconceptions about the company,
将军希望
and the general wants
开诚布公
to, uh, open the books.
我来  就是想告诉你事实
i'm here to... provide facts
并且帮助你分析
and to help you process them.
如果你的事实指的是"锡拉"内的信息
if by facts, you mean what's on scylla
以及  我妈妈曾为"公司"工作过
and that my mother once worked for the company,
我早就知道了
i already know these things.
曾经
"worked"?
你妈妈
your mother...
还在为我们工作
works for us.
你妈妈还活着
your mother is alive.
-我们三点才开业  -我来找个人
we don't open till 3:00. sorry.i'm just looking for someone.
我不知道名字
haven't got the guy's name,
但他给这里打过电话
uh, but he called here yesterday
三次  纽约人  深色头发
about three times. new yorker, dark hair,
带点灰色
bits of gray.
你知道在哪可以找到他吗
you know where i can find him?
对不起  帮不了你
uh, yeah, i can't help you. sorry.
确定吗
you sure?
哥们  你耳朵有问题吗
my man, you need to check your ears,
他说了不知道你找的人
all right, 'cause he just said we don't know who you're talking about.
-真的吗  -没错
is that right? yeah, that's right.
美女知道吗
well, what about blondie?
你只有两秒钟
you've got about two seconds...
说吧
how about it?
我不知道他的名字
i don't know his name.
快说
how about it!
我不知道他的名字  他...
i don't know his name.he works...
他女朋友在这工作
this girl... works here, he dates her.
你带我去找她
you're gonna take me to her.
这一切真是
well, this is all just..
太"迷人"了  医生
fascinating, doctor.
我不知道怎么说才好
i don't know how better to say this.
她离开你和你哥哥  是为了保护你们
she left you and your brother to protect you.
以免受到太阳能合成工作的威胁吗
from the dangers of solar synthesis work?
我知道"锡拉"内的东西
i know what's on scylla.
有一定威胁  你和林肯可能会被绑架
there were threats, you and lincoln might be kidnapped.
你们当时很危险
you were in imminent danger.
真的吗
really.
我哥哥被捆在电椅上的时候
where was she when my brother was strapped
她在哪
to an electric chair?
她一直在马达加斯加的雨林里工作
she'd been working in a madagascar rain forest,
没有卫星信号
without satellite access.
或者她已经过世25年了
or she wasn't alive, hasn't been for 25 years,
这些都是你编的
and this is all fiction.
因为你妈妈的研究  科尔多瓦外的荒地
there's a million acres, corn and soy, outside cordoba
现在变成了绿油油的田地
that was arid scrub before your mother's research.
那不是我编的
that's not fiction,
那些食物
that's food...
可以养活成千
for thousands.
上万的人
millions.
"锡拉"上还有很多
there's so much more
你不知道的事情
on scylla than you know.
听起来  我们还有很多要谈
it sounds like we'd have a lot to talk about.
为什么不直接给她打电话
why don't you get her on the phone.
等你准备好
when you're ready.
现在就行
no time like the present.
当你准备好
when you're ready...
加入她
to join her.
加入我们
us.
这是我这次谈话的
that's... what this conversation
重点
is about.
加入
joining...
"公司"
the company.
喂  埃里卡  是我
hey, erica, it's me.
你来了吗
so, are you coming?
我需要和你谈谈
i really need to talk to you.
她在路上了
she's on her way.
我的天啊
oh, my god!
为什么他要打酒吧的电话  而不打给埃里卡呢
why'd this guy call the club's phone and not erica's?
我...他们经常吵架
i... they fight a lot,
她不接电话  他就打酒吧的电话
so when she doesn't answer, he calls the club.
你找他干什么
what do you want with this guy?
他拿了我的东西
he took something that belongs to me.
我要拿回来
i want it back.
在那
there.
埃里卡在那
there's erica.
在这等着
wait here.
把他搞定
get him stitched up.
大个子
big guy.
光头  疯子
shaved head. crazy.
-他到底是谁  -我不知道
- who the hell is he? - i don't know.
他相信 你是那个女人的朋友
he bought the whole thing about you being friends
的话了
with this chick or whatever?
他不知道我才是你女朋友
he didn't know i was with you,
当他知道时  他只想躲别人的子弹
and by the time he did, he was trying not to get shot.
你做得很好
you did good.
我只想抽支烟
i just need a smoke so bad.
完了
oh, no.
怎么了
what?
我的钱包
my wallet.
这是那个陷害我的小妞的
this is the chick who set me up.
我们找到她  就能找到那个人
we find her, we find our guy.
在酒吧打架  公共场所开枪
busting up clubs, firing shots in public.
你再这么干下去  我们就别想在这呆了
you keep that up and we're not going to last here much longer.
我可没打算在这久留  你想吗
i don't plan on staying here very long. you?
瞧  这就是我为什么佩服将军
see, that's why i have to give it up to the general.
他把四个敌人放在一起  保准起内讧
he puts four enemies together, guaranteed dissension.
但不会有同谋造反
no alliances form against him.
这是那家伙女友的地址
this is our guy's girlfriend's address.
他估计跑路了
he's probably gone,
看看能找到什么
but see what you can find.
这就是蒂亚
this is tia.
你想知道我对他们的谈话的想法吗
do you want to know what i think they were talking about?
我不管
i don't care.
只要他们不挡我的道
just as long as they keep out of my way.
你也一样
same with you.
让她进来
send her in.
莎拉  你看来
sarah! you're looking...
精神不错
rested.
那宾馆怎么样
how is the hotel?
我想在迈克尔康复期间
i would like to offer my professional
提供我的专业协助
assistance in michael's rehabilitation.
很好
kind...
但他接受的是最优秀的照顾
but he's receiving excellent care.
你没必要担心
there's nothing for you to worry about.
不管你为他准备了什么
whatever it is you have planned for him,
我只想帮忙维持他的健康
i would simply like to help maintain his health.
很感激你  但是不行
and that's appreciated, but it's impossible.
相信我  现在最好
believe me, you serve michael best
跟迈克尔保持一定距离
at a distance right now.
相信我
trust me.
我只想看看他是否安好
i have no agenda apart from simply...
别无所求
wanting to see that he's okay.
三天或一星期后
and in three days to a week,
他就会回到你爱的怀抱
he'll be back in your loving arms forever.
好的  我没这个耐心
okay, i'm not that patient.
放任一下自己吧
indulge yourself.
坐在泳池边
sit by the pool,
想象一下将来
envision the future:
财政安全
financial security,
迈克尔的才干能在世界范围内应用
michael's talents being utilized on a global scale,
你能在旁看他创新
you beside him innovating.
迈克尔的才干能在世界范围内应用
michael's talents being utilized on a global scale?
我只是想最大化他的潜力
i'm simply trying to maximize his potential.
你的也是
yours, too.
你对他做了什么
what's being done to him?
我要结束这种猫捉老鼠的游戏
i'm putting an end to this exhausting cat-and-mouse.
谢谢你专程来访
thank you for stopping by.
激进建筑学一直被
"radical architecture is a rejection of all formal
传统方式所反对
and moral parameters."
出自你的论文
from your thesis.
严重扭曲了某人的话
someone else's words heavily paraphrased.
并且这只适用于建筑和结构
and it pertains to buildings, structures.
我认为你是用于隐喻
i think you meant it as a metaphor.
结果印证方式吗
what, that the ends justify the means?
这跟你母亲的理论
which neatly
惊人的一致
coincides with your mother's philosophy.
你知不知道  30年前
did you know that she had an almost identical quote
她在论文里
in her thesis?
引述过几乎同样一句话
from 30 years ago.
你倒是做了不少功课啊
you've done a lot of homework.
只是找些话题
just a few conversations.
我猜你们在"公司"的圣诞派对上
let me guess. you two had some kind of moment
有过一段美妙时光吧
at the company Christmas party?
我认识你母亲很久了
I’ve known your mother for years.
了解到你和她一样聪明绝顶
well enough to know you've got the same brilliant mind
很有幽默感
and the same sense of humor, for that matter.
这和幽默没关系吧
I’m guessing this isn't about my sense of humor.
她最初
she was just
也不愿加入"公司"
as resistant to joining the company,
但当她了解了事实
but then she learned the truth.
如果你指"公司"是为了拯救世界
if the truth is that the company is all about saving the world,
我不相信
I don't buy it.
如果我母亲在"公司"如此才华出众
and if my mother is so brilliant and active in the company,
你想让我干吗
what do you want with me?
一个全球性功能全面的
a fully functioning scylla project would exist
"锡拉"工程
on a global scale.
单凭一个人是做不到的
it can't be managed by one person.
但两个
but two...
心有灵犀的天才
equally formidable, working in lockstep?
绝对没问题
absolutely.
想法很好
that's very good.
你什么都想到了
you've clearly thought of everything.
迈克尔
michael...
如果我在骗你
if i weren't telling you the truth,
我又怎么能拿到这个东西
how would i have gotten this?
她只是个和罪犯交往的傻妞
this is just a stupid girl who dates a criminal.
完全是浪费时间
this is a waste of time.
布伦斯的领导风范
a signature of burrows' leadership.
我们要调整一下
all right, we need to make a shift.
巴格维尔  我现在告诉你
bagwell, i'm telling you right now,
如果你在我行动时手软
if i make my play and you go soft,
我就把你扔下阳台
i will sail you off that loft balcony
鬼都不会关心
and no one will bat an eye.
我的目标很明确  唐
my aim is true, don.
相信我
keep it in your pants.
我相信你  行了吧
i'll keep it in my pants, all right?
更改体制的回报  说声"是"
all right, all in favor of changing the regime, say "aye."
是  长官
aye, aye, captain.
好的  那布伦斯就滚蛋了
aye. all right, burrows is out.
很好  发过来
good, great. send it.
"公司"在传蒂亚的信用卡记录
the company's e-mailing tia's credit card history.
我越来越觉得这是内部工作
you know, i'm thinking more and more that this is an inside job.
-为什么  -有几个理由
-why?  -a couple reasons.
他带到见面地点的设备
the hardware he brought to the meet.
能当场读出"锡拉"的内容
he could read scylla right on the spot.
自从他消失后
since he's disappeared,
我应该能找到他  但却不行
i should be able to find this man, and i can't.
通常找不到的人  就是"公司"的
people you can't find are usually company.
那又怎么样
how does that change anything?
不怎样
it doesn't.
只是一切更难了
it just makes everything harder.
林肯
lincoln...
我们什么时候才能开始
when are we going to get this out of the way?
什么
what?
我一生诱惑了那么多男人
of all the mercenary humps i've thrown at guys
我也该得到我心仪的那个
in my lifetime, i think i'm due for one i want.
别自作多情了
don't flatter yourself.
太晚了
too late.
说出来吧
name it.
任何事都可以
and i do mean anything.
屁都没找到
an ol' fat load of nothin'!
什么都没有
a big ol' goose egg.
啥都没有  旧通讯录  旧照片
nothing. old address books, photographs,
电脑上的硬盘
hard drive from her computer.
我查了她的邮件和网站
i checked her e-mails and her web sites.
没有任何我们想要的信息
there's nothing from our guy.
你确定查这女的有用吗
are you sure this girlfriend route is the way to go here?
因为我开始觉得  我们在做无用功
because this is starting to feel like a wasted trip.
"公司"要多久才能把
how long is it gonna take the company
里面的东西读出来
to pull everything off this thing?
几小时吧
a couple hours.
行了  林肯  不如这样
all right, linc, this is the deal.
我们很感激你的努力
look, we appreciate your effort,
但我和巴格维尔做了次表决
but bagwell and i took a vote,
我们在福州行动  但你的能力不够
and this being florida and all, you came up a little bit short.
什么意思
meaning?
你不是一把手
you're not in charge.
那谁是
who is?
-他  -没错
him. yeah.
莽夫行事的方式
the bull-in-the-china-shop routine
可能在你偷东西时管用
might have worked when you were stealing gumballs,
但我们现在都虎落平阳
but our asses are on the line now, okay?
而且都和将军达成协议
and we all have deals with the general.
所以只能这样
so that's the way it's gonna be.
况且  连格雷琴都没有帮你说话
and if you notice, even gretchen hasn't leapt to your defense.
林肯  就让他当头吧
linc, just let him wear his crown.
如果他没想过把东西卖了就行
i would if i thought he wasn't gonna sell this thing.
只是我一个人这么想过吗
oh, what, am i the only one who's thought about that?
林肯  听着
look, here's the deal, linc.
到时候  会让你当当头
at some point, you'll have a vote.
但是在那之前  你没戏了
but until then, you're done, all right?
我们不听你的了
we're shuttin' you down, okay?
你不是头头了
you're no longer in charge.
看来又得重新投票了
uh-oh, looks like there's been a recount.
来的不是时候
bad time?
不  正是时候
no, perfect.
你再不听从我的指挥
the second you stop doing what i tell you to do,
我就毙了你
i'm gonna blow your brains out.
把她找回来
bring her back.
这次不一样
it's not gonna be the same.
想起什么了吗
stir any memories?
我当时十岁  我们去杰克逊洞野营
i was ten. we were on a camping trip in jackson hole.
钓鱼  远足
fishing, hiking.
一家人围坐在篝火旁
family huddled under a blanket in front of the bonfire.
你可以停了
you can stop now.
为什么  因为两年后这一切都消失了
why? because two years later it was gone?
相片中的四个人
you know, three of the four
有三个都还活着
people in this photograph are still alive.
你想说什么
so what are you suggesting,
让我拿起鱼竿
grab my fishing pole?
为全家在怀俄明州重聚准备吗
time for a...a family reunion in wyoming?
你想去哪都行
or wherever you like.
别告诉我  你不希望实现这个
don't tell me it's something you haven't wished for.
我所希望的  都是不现实的东西
i wished for a lot of unrealistic things.
我也已经忘了
i got over them, too.
为什么
why,
我们可以让它变成现实
when we can make this happen?
这些照片随时随地都可以拍
these pictures could have been taken anywhere at any time.
在你进监狱前
before you were incarcerated,
每周年祭  你都会去她墓碑前看她
you'd go to visit her grave on the anniversary
够了  别说了
all right, enough.
你会带一束蓝色鸢尾
you'd bring a bouquet of blue irises.
在那里坐一小时
you'd sit for an hour.
别说了
i said stop it.
离开时  会拿一朵
when you'd leave, you'd take a flower
别在翻领上
and pin it to your lapel.
她每年都看你这么做
she watched you do this every year.
她看到了你所背负的痛苦
she's seen the pain you carry.
她想弥补
she wants to make amends.
够了
all right!
你是做了不少功课  真有你的
so you did a little digging. good for you.
但你说的都是谎言
but everything out of your mouth is a lie,
我一个字都不相信
and i don't believe a word of it.
你省省吧
so let's just stop.
别再说了
let's just stop.
这是蒂亚的住址
that's tia's address
查看一下
right there. pull it up.
她住在这  工作地点在这  但是昨天
all right, she lives here, works here, but yesterday
中午时分  她在蓝鸟酒吧
she used her credit card to buy a drink
用信用卡买了点酒
at the pelican club a little after noon,
1点左右  去礼品店
and then she picked up something at the gift shop
买了些东西
a little after 1:00.
等他男友下船
waiting for her boyfriend to debark.
是上岸
disembark.
-那他已经在城里了  -对
he's already in town. yeah.
那他应该住在港口
then he lives in the marina.
这也可能是另一个内部工作的原因
or this is another reason to think it's an inside job.
如果他和"公司"的人工作
if he's working with someone from the company,
他们不会希望名字出现在航空乘客名单上
they wouldn't want their names on any flight manifests.
没错  他们想暗中
all right, they're trying to get scylla
将"锡拉"用船运出境
out of the country by boat undetected.
我们走
let's go.
阿历克斯
alex, yeah?
谢谢你能来
thanks for coming when you did, man.
你信守诺言帮过我  我欠你的
you helped me like you said you would. i owe you.
由我来谈
okay, i'll do the talking.
你们在这里等
you guys wait here.
阿历克斯  我们走
alex, let's go.
下午好
afternoon.
你好吗
how's it going?
能帮你们什么吗
what can i do you for?
认得她吗
recognize her?
她叫蒂亚・海顿
her name's tia hayden.
不认识
can't say i do. wish i did.
长得倒挺漂亮
nice little tomato there.
她昨天和一个男人来过
she was in here yesterday with a man.
帮不了你们
can't help.
抱歉
sorry.
我是唐・赛尔夫  国安局的
don self, homeland security.
这是我搭档布鲁斯・雷布拉奇
and this is my partner bruce liberace.
没什么关系
no relation.
我们正和外资调控部门合作
our department is working with the office
听说过吗
of foreign assets control. have you heard of them?
听过
yep.
相信你也听过  我们在调查
I bet you have. we're looking into smuggling
古巴雪茄走私案
and contraband transportation of cuban cigars.
我发誓  这里没有
none here, swear to god.
行了  那得我们说了算
all right, well, that's for us to decide.
大概要一周
it's going to take about a week,
在此期间你要关门大吉
and it's going to involve shutting down this entire marina...
没错
oh, yeah.
一个星期
...for about a week.
-或者  -她来过
or... she was here
和你们说的那个人一起
with that guy you were talking about.
他想知道私人船只停在哪
he wanted to know which berth a private charter was docking in.
他要我把船停远一点  我照办了
he asked me to move it further down the dock, which i did.
避开海岸巡逻队
further away from the coast guard slip?
我没问  我也没收钱
i didn't ask. and i didn't accept any money.
如果他说付过款  那是骗人的
if he said he paid me, he's lying.
出发点呢
what's the point of departure?
巴拿马的拿骚  双程
nassau, bahamas. round trip.
什么时候抵达
when does it arrive?
已经到了
arrived.
各位好  我是唐・赛尔夫
hey, everybody! okay, my name is don self!
国安局的
homeland security.
我和同事都希望你们有个快乐安全的旅程
my colleagues and i are hoping that you guys have a wonderful
但是
and safe trip. unfortunately,
我们要快速进行一次行李检查
we're going to have to do a quick luggage check search.
不会占用很多时间
shouldn't take more than a minute, folks.
只请各位配合
your cooperation is all that's required.
打开你的包
open your bags.
跪下
get on your knees!
"锡拉"在哪
where is it? where's scylla?
里面是什么
what have you got in here?
3卷大麻
three joints.
我还在服缓刑
i'm on probation.
我会被抓回监狱吗
is this going to send me back?
给自己做个头盔  老弟
make yourself a helmet, pal.
就像小时候那样
just like old times.
把她找回来
bring her back.
你知道我做不到
you know i can't do that.
我的能力有限
but, look, there's some stuff that i can do.
这次不一样
it's not going to be the same,
但我们会弄明白的
but we're going to figure it out.
无论如何
and, no matter what,
我们都会在一起
it's still going to be me and you.
我很高兴你在山上过得开心
i am thrilled that you're enjoying your trip to the mountains,
但这可不是度假
but it's not an open-ended vacation.
斯科菲尔德现在身心疲惫  精神沮丧
scofield's exhausted. despondent.
很抗拒  但也是个典型弃儿
he's very resistant, but a classic abandoned child.
他会屈服的
he'll come around.
需要多久  医生
time frame, doctor?
不用药的话  3天
unaided, three days.
如果用喷妥撒呢
with the pentothal?
会快些  但这相当于药物叶切断术
sooner, but it's nearly a chemical lobotomy.
如果他能自愿归顺  那将是他的决心
but, if he turns on his own, it'll be his decision,
他的思维
his reasoning.
他就能永远归顺我们
we'll own him forever.
斯科菲尔德很狡猾
scofield's squirrelly.
不经过历练  我是不会相信他的
i won't trust him till he walks hot coals.
我相信能让他转变
i think i can get him there.
很好  但如果
good. but, if
我发现你被他耍了  医生
i find out he's been playing you, doctor,
你也会接受跟他一样的叶切断术
you'll get the same lobotomy as scofield.
尽快搞定
just get it done.
快走
Let's go.
快上车
In the van.
开车
Go.
如果解开手铐后  你有什么举动
if you fight when those cuffs are off,
警卫们不会手下留情
the guards will stomp the life out of you.
知道了
yeah.
抱歉  行动粗鲁了些
forgive the dramatics.
不能让"公司"知道我们见面
the company can't know i'm talking to you.
你就是"公司"的人  你是他女儿
you are the company. you're his daughter.
你还想不想找到迈克尔・斯科菲尔德
do you want to find michael scofield?
当然想
of course i do.
他就在60英里外
it's 60 miles northeast
市区的东北边  最好快点行动
of downtown. i'd move quickly.
他们对他做了什么
what are they doing to him?
请他喝柠檬汁
having lemonade.
他们想改造他的思想
they're carving out his personality.
这就是他们招募的方式
that's how they recruit.
你这是在设计我
or you're setting me up.
秘密战虽不光彩
clandestine warfare isn't pretty,
但交战规则
but the rules of engagement
不包括折磨和杀戮无辜者
don't include killing and torturing the innocent.
至少我不会
at least not for me.
迈克尔正在进行快速洗脑
michael is the object of a quick and nasty
而你在浪费时间
process, and you're wasting time.
走吧
out.
快
我们要安全摄像头的录像
we need the footage from that security camera.
无意冒犯二位  但我
not to offend either of you, but i took
打电话找了律师
the liberty of calling my attorney
询问你们的权利范围
to find out exactly what the scope of your authority is here,
-他告诉我  -只管交出来  行吧
- and he tells me... - just get the tape, all right?
好
Sure
或者我们漏掉了"锡拉"
either we missed scylla...
不可能漏掉
no, no, no. we did not miss scylla.
我们翻了每一个包
we searched every bag.
也许买家已经在船上了
then maybe the buyer was already on the boat,
也要上岸  是吧
and was disembarking, right?
如果他们不想在航空乘客名单上留下名字
i mean, if they don't want their names on any flight manifest,
他们也许会偷溜上去
maybe they just eased back on in.
那也不是最糟的
that wouldn't be the worst news.
意味着他们在迈阿密
that means they're in miami.
好
Right.
戴上你那不光彩的徽章  到船上去
So get yourself back down with your disgraced badge to steamboat willie,
让他把船上每个人的名字都供出来
And have him cough up every name of every person on that boat coming off.
行啊  很好
Okay, that's good,
他们可能从巴哈马坐低等船
Because they probably would have traveled in on a
而且用真名过来  对吗
Low-grade charter from the bahamas, and used their real names, right?
计划真不错
That would be a good plan.
他还好吗
How is he?
他还活着
He's alive.
我们拿到"锡拉"后
So we get scylla.
我们就自由了  潘姆  还有LJ
Then we're free, all of us-- pam, lj...
突然之间  "公司"有良心了吗
All of a sudden, the company grew a heart?
他们也对我们厌烦了
They're just tired of us.
他们只想要回"锡拉"
They want scylla back. that's it.
我们从来没有他们真正想要的东西
Then we never really had anything they wanted.
没错  我们现在有筹码了
Exactly. now we got leverage.
现在还没有
We don't have it yet.
有发现吗
Anything?
没有
No.
还没有
Nothing yet.
没有
Nothing.
林肯  你不明白
No, lincoln, you don't understand.
她说招募的方式  让我很担心
The way she said "recruit" made my stomach turn.
他们会折磨他的
They're going to torture him.
我们拿到"锡拉"前  他至少能照顾自己一天
He can take care of himself, at least for one day, until we get scylla.
林肯  他得待在加护病房
Lincoln, he needs to be in the icu.
你有什么计划
What's your plan?
劫他出来吗
Break him out?
我不知道  我没有计划
I don't know. I don't have one.
那你只是给他和我们带来危险
Well, you're putting him and us at risk.
我们回洛城之前  你就待在宾馆里
Just stay in the hotel until we get back to l.a.
好吗
All right?
唐克雷蒂找到她的白马王子了
Tancredi got the location of her shining knight.
她现在可能去找他了
She may be heading there now.
做得好  巴格维尔
Exemplary, bagwell.
谢谢夸奖  先生
Thank you, sir.
说话要算话  不是想唠叨  我只是想
A deal's a deal, right? not to be a broken record, but all I ask...
将军  我认为我们这里有实质性进展
But I think we're making some real progress, general.
斯布家族对"公司"而言  虽是一笔财富
The scofield/burrows family would have been a formidable asset to the
但他的人执意捣乱  我们就要采取行动
Company, but since his lapdog insists on complicating matters, we move on.
将军  我们能搞定一个女人
General, we can handle a lone female.
没错  是只有一个
If, indeed, that's what we're dealing with.
但根据我的经验  一个人会引来很多人
But it's my experience, that with the one comes many.
现在就动手  医生
Do it now, doctor.
还要一小时  他刚吃饭  我不想让他吐
I need an hour. he just ate. I don't want him to aspirate.
马上  医生
Now, doctor.
我要斯科菲尔德能顺利转移
I want scofield pliable for transit.
你的车20分钟后到
Your vehicle arrives in 20 minutes.
万一我们不能使他苏醒呢
And if we can't revive him?
那就认命
C'est la vie!
迈克尔  出来  我们谈谈
Michael, come out. we need to talk.
给自己做个头盔  老弟
make yourself a helmet, pal.
没错
That's it!
就是他
That's our guy!
蒂亚就在他旁边
There's tia right beside him.
我们把图像导出来  交给"公司"
We've got to pull that image, get it to the company,
让他们找出他
And have them match it.
格雷琴去哪了
Where's gretchen?
你怎么找到我的
How'd you find me?
能发现你的照片
Once I found your mug shot,
再找你的手机号就不难了
It really wasn't that hard getting your legit cell number.
我现在来了
well, now i'm here.
你想怎样
what do you want?
你在洛城一直不要求支援
you never bothered to ask back in los angeles
一心只想杀了我
you were too busy planning on killing me
但事实上  我为"公司"工作
but i actually worked for the company.
我知道你是谁
i know who you are.
我再问一次
and i'll ask it again.
你想怎样
what do you want?
解决你的问题  斯科特
to solve your problems, scott.
这是我今天的头等大事
i mean, it is what gets me up out of bed in the morning.
你有大麻烦
you have a big problem, and so does
你的老板也一样
whoever it is you're working for.
你肯定知道
and you obviously know that
要不就不会来见我了
or you wouldn't have graced me with your presence.
你可以搞定吗
and you can make that problem disappear?
又快又彻底
quickly and completely.
但要额外好处
with an extra added bonus.
或者说  大有好处
crucial, i might add.
然后我会编个故事
i then feed the company a story
让"公司"的人到别处找你
that has them looking elsewhere.
也就说你很有价值
meaning you're invaluable
-求我别杀你  -对
and please don't kill you. yeah.
但不用求
without the "please."
你要多少钱
how much?
很多
a lot.
我跟你说话时  你不看着我
and it's about to double here in a second
我就要求双倍的钱
if you don't look at me when i'm talking to you.
去和你老板商量
you go run and talk it over with your boss.
定了数目再给我电话
call me with a number.
我可以代表他们跟你谈
i'm authorized to negotiate on their behalf.
如果你帮我
if you serve up
除掉追查我们的人  并能让"公司"找不到我们
whoever's looking for us and get the company off our scent--
一千万
$10 million.
最终价格
best and final offer.
多要一分钱
ask for a penny more and i'll shoot you
我就杀了你
in the chest and take my chances.
别紧张  迈克尔
take it easy, michael.
这
this...
是为你好
is for your own good.
什么声音
what was that?
好像是热水器
sounded like the water heater.
卫生间传来的
came from the bathroom.
捡起来
pick it up!
给医生注射
now give the doctor his medicine.
不
no.
铐到床柱上
bedpost.
这儿  在卧室
in here, in the bedroom.
快点
come on!
谢谢  很好  有其他消息就告诉我
thank you. perfect. let me know if you hear anything else.
你去哪了
where the hell you been?
查清整件事
figuring this whole thing out.
我知道买家是谁了
i know who it is.the buyer.
他叫劳伦斯・威考特
his name is lawrence wilcott and he's been working
为"公司"工作十年了
for the company for ten years.
你怎么知道的
how did you figure that out?
我在"公司"内外
i still have friends on the inside,
还有不少朋友
and on the outside of the company.
我合并了一些头像
i've been putting together a profile,
缩小范围
narrowing down the candidates.
威考特昨天在波哥大
wilcott got on a plane in Bogota
乘飞机飞往巴哈马
and flew to the bahamas yesterday
然后上船
and then got on a boat.
在洛城抢走"锡拉"的家伙
the guy who took scylla off us in l.a.?
我们从录像上取到他的头像
we pulled his image off the security tape.
"公司"正在做吻合对比
company's running a recognition match right now.
不错  但那要一整天
that's great, but that's going to take all day.
你知道他现在在哪吗  和威考特一起
do you know where he is right now? with wilcott.
我们得出发了
we need to go now.
因为
because better yet,
我知道威考特在哪
i know where wilcott's staying.
好的  我们得赶在"锡拉"转移前行动
okay, we need to move before scylla does.
走吧
let's go.
转身  双手抱头
turn around!Hands on your head.
快开车  我们要闪开
punch it, we gotta get out of here!
迈克尔  快进来
Michael, get in!
他租下了整层顶楼
he's rented out the entire top floor.
安保严密
Security at every point.
我们可以贿赂一个员工
We might want to get to an employee. bribe 'em.
摩天大楼里的高端"公司"
top level company in a big glass building.
不许乱动
nice and slow.
举起手来
get your hands up.
都在这里了吗
this is everyone?
婊子
you whore.
你就是个婊子
you're a whore,
你娘也是个婊子
and your mother was a whore,
她奶奶  你爹
and her mother, and your father
以前就在加油站乱搞
used to turn tricks at a gas station,
因为他也是个男妓
'cause he was a whore, too.
再见  阿姨
bye, auntie.
抱歉  我现在更关心生活
sorry, but right now i want my life back
而不是钱
more than i want your money.
"锡拉"在哪
where's scylla?
行  我们谈吧
well, let's talk about that, okay?
在哪
let's. where is it?
我能搞到它
i can get it.
他不能
no, he can't.
他在拖延时间  林肯  "锡拉"已经没了
he's stalling, linc. it's gone.
没错
you're right.
你们都滚一边去吧
and since all you guys can kiss my ass,
我现在只想完成一件事
there's only one thing i want to accomplish right now.
劳伦斯・威考特
lawrence wilcott?
租下了整层楼
the whole floor of the hotel rented out?
瞎编的
made it up.
你不知道他为谁卖命吗
you have no idea who this guy was working for?
不知道
no.
不清楚
no clue.
我们得闪人了  伙计们
we gotta pull the pin here, guys.
就算她最后改变主意了
just because she switched sides at the last second
但不意味着她之前没想杀我们
doesn't mean she wasn't going to kill us two minutes ago, okay?
杀了她  不能把她留给警察
kill her. all right, we're not leaving her here
我们也不能送她去医院
for the cops and we're not taking her
为什么
to the hospital. why?
我刚才救了你们
i didn't let you get slaughtered.
她还有个孩子
she's got a kid.
那又怎么样
so what?
我们是在杀她女儿吗
are we killing the kid?
那孩子根本不知道这是她妈妈
the kid doesn't even know it's her mother.
快点  林肯  开枪吧
come on, linc, pull the trigger. do it.
孩子名叫艾米丽
her name's emily.
只有八岁  算了吧
she's only eight years old. come on.
动手吧
Do it.
我们不是他们
we're not them.
保守秘密
you keep your mouth shut,
探监期间还能见你孩子
and you get to see your kid in visitation.
我知道如果在监狱乱说  将军会怎么处置我
i know what the general will do to me if I talk in prison.
相信我
believe me.
我很了解他
i know him well.
就这么算了吗
are you serious?
快走  快
let's go, let's go.
怎么了
what happened?
你一句话都不说
you haven't said a word.
我觉得我母亲还活着
i think my mother's alive.
是他的电话  接吧
that's his cell phone. answer it.
喂
hello.
你的人死了
your boy's dead.
我会找出你
and now i'm coming after you.
听清楚了吗
did you hear me?
不管你是谁  我会找出你
whoever you are, i'm coming after you.
是谁
who was that?
我儿子
it was my son.
林肯
Lincoln.